Name: Sabit Alizade

Contact Information:

- Email: sabit@engineer.com

contact@sabitalizade.com

- Address: Baku, Azerbaijan

- Phone: +994706717474

- Github: https://github.com/sabitalizade

- Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/sabitalizade

- Website: https://sabitalizade.com

Summary:

Experienced software developer with 2 years of experience in full-stack web development using JavaScript, TypeScript, OOP, Node js, React, Docker, Git, Mongodb and SQL. Strong background in developing, testing, and deploying software solutions. Proven ability to adapt to new technologies and work in a team environment.

Experience:

Software Developer, Pasha Bank (Oct 2024 – Present)

- Working in an Agile team, actively participating in ceremonies such as stand-ups, planning, and retrospectives.
- Developing large-scale banking applications serving millions of users.
- Contributing to code reviews and enforcing high-quality standards across the codebase.
- Mentoring junior developers and assisting them in improving their skills.
- Collaborating with product, QA, and DevOps teams to deliver new features efficiently.

Software Supervisor, Socar Trading (2023 – Oct 2024)

- Led a team of software developers in successful project delivery using JavaScript, Node.js, React, Docker, Git, and SQL.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to gather requirements and design scalable software solutions.
- Managed project timelines, budgets, and resource allocation.
- Conducted code reviews and implemented best practices.
- Mentored junior team members and guided their growth.

Software Developer, EiLink R&D (2022 – Oct 2024)

- Worked as a frontend developer and then as a full-stack developer on a supply chain management product.
- Developed and maintained software applications using JavaScript, Node.js, React, and SQL.
- Implemented Microservice architecture, and developed a notification socket service using Node.js and MongoDB.
- Worked in an Agile development environment and collaborated with other developers and stakeholders to understand requirements and design software solutions.

JavaScript Developer, AT-Geotech (2021-2022)

- Developed an ERP system using jQuery, React, and SQL.
- Worked with a team to understand the requirements and design software solutions.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure high-quality codebase.

Frontend Developer, Meal Ordering Startup (2021-2023)

- Developed 90% of a merchant app for a meal ordering startup similar to Uber Eats using React, Redux, and Ant Design.
- Continuously support and maintain the app, fixing bugs and adding new features.
- Worked with a team to understand the requirements and design software solutions.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure high-quality codebase.

Skills:

- Proficient in JavaScript, Node.js,Python, Golang, React, Redux, React Query, React Native, SQL, MongoDB, Docker, Git, Knex.js, and Express.js.
- Experience with Microservice architecture and Go Lang.
- Strong understanding of web development principles and best practices.
- Experience with Agile development methodologies.
- Strong problem-solving and analytical skills.

Education:

- Master of Regulation of Economy, Baku State University, Baku, Azerbaijan (2017-2019)
- Bachelor of Economy, Nakhchivan State University, Nakhchivan, Azerbaijan (2013-2017)